{
    "id": "920213a87b9e4fbea5bfbb8745dd4228",
    "title": "Adjective + Preposition Combinations",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "1816a3b0176845cc8e1a07dd3ac7b6eb",
            "title": "Adjective + Preposition",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "He has been married .................................. her for more than three decades.",
                    "description": "Married is followed by the preposition 'to'.",
                    "answers": [
                        "with",
                        "to",
                        "for"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The Irish are very proud ..................................... their sense of humor.",
                    "description": "The adjective proud is followed by the preposition of.",
                    "answers": [
                        "about",
                        "of",
                        "in"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "He is interested ..................................... the supernatural.",
                    "description": "Interested is followed by the preposition in. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "at",
                        "in",
                        "with"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I am pleased ............................................. your promotion.",
                    "description": "Pleased is followed by the preposition about. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "for",
                        "about",
                        "with"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "She was angry ........................................ me for revealing her secret.",
                    "description": "Angry is usually followed by the preposition. Sometimes at is also possible. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "on",
                        "with",
                        "to"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I am getting anxious ............................................. his health.",
                    "description": "Anxious about means worried about. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "for",
                        "to",
                        "about"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "We are all anxious ............................................. an amicable solution to this problem.",
                    "description": "Anxious for means eager to have. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "about",
                        "to",
                        "for"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "She is anxious ....................................... reunite with her family.",
                    "description": "When anxious is followed by a to-infinitive, it means eager. The above sentence means: She is eager to reunite with her family. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "about",
                        "for",
                        "to"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "You can't be independent ...................................... your parents until you find a job.",
                    "description": "Independent is followed by of. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "for",
                        "of",
                        "from"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Why can't you be polite ....................................... him?",
                    "description": "Polite is followed by to.",
                    "answers": [
                        "with",
                        "to",
                        "at"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Both parents are responsible ....................................... raising a child.",
                    "description": "Responsible is followed by for. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "to",
                        "for",
                        "about"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I feel really sorry ........................................... his wife.",
                    "description": "You feel sorry for a person. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "for",
                        "about",
                        "at"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}